We've discussed how an agent might choose actions with the goal of
我们讨论了智能体如何选择动作以便实现最大化预期回报这一目标
maximizing expected return but we need to dig a bit deeper.
但是我们还需要深入了解这方面的知识
For instance, consider our puppy agent,
例如 对于我们的小狗智能体
how does he predict how much reward he could get at any point in the future?
它可以如何预测在未来的任何时间点 它能够获得多少奖励
Puppies can live for decades.
小狗可以活十几年
Can he really be expected to have just as much of an idea of
它现在知道可以获得的奖励数
how much reward he'll get now as he does five years from now?
与五年之后知道可以获得的奖励真的一样吗
Does it make more sense to consider that it's not entirely
是否它不知道未来会怎样这个理论更合理
clear what the future holds especially if the puppy is still learning,
尤其是如果小狗依然在学习
proposing, and testing hypotheses and changing his strategy?
提出假设 测试假设并更改策略
It's unlikely that he'll know one thousand times steps
它不太可能知道在未来第 1000 个时间步
in advance what his reward potential is likely to be.
它能获得的奖励潜力是多少
In general, the puppy is likely to have a much better idea of what's
通常 与很远的未来相比
likely to happen in the near future than he does for a distant time points.
小狗更有可能知道不久将来的状况
Along these lines then,
那么 当前奖励的权重
should present reward carry the same weight as future reward?
应该和未来奖励的权重一样吗？
Maybe it makes more sense to value rewards that come sooner more highly,
或许应该将不久将来的奖励权重设置更高
since those rewards are more predictable.
因为这些奖励更容易预测
That is, if I told you,
也就是说 如果我告诉你
"I'll either definitely give you a marshmallow
“我肯定现在会给你一个棉花糖
now or probably give you one a day from now."
或者明天可能会给一个”
Wouldn't you prefer to just have it now?
难道你不会立即拿走棉花糖吗？
Whatever today's marshmallow is worth to you,
今天的棉花糖对你的价值有多大
tomorrow's marshmallow is probably only worth a percentage of that to you.
明天的棉花糖对你来说可能只有一定百分比的价值
Say, 90 percent or 10 percent less than today's marshmallow.
例如价值是 90% 或比今天的低 10%
After all, there's a chance you might not even get it.
毕竟你可能根本拿不到这个棉花糖
If we continue the trend with the day after tomorrow's marshmallow,
如果我们继续这种模式
which is even less guaranteed,
后天的棉花糖可能性更小
well, it would make sense that it's worth even less.
因此价值更低
This situation motivates the idea of discounting and discounted return.
这就引出了折扣和折扣回报这个概念
Remember that the goal of the agent is always to maximize cumulative reward.
注意 智能体的目标始终是最大化累积奖励
And towards this end,
在实现此目标时
at an arbitrary time step t,
在随机时间步 t
it can choose the action that maximizes the return.
它可以选择最大化回报的动作
And currently, each time step from t plus
目前 t+1 之后的每个时间步
one onward has an equal say in how the agent should make decisions.
对于智能体的决策制定有相同的影响
What if instead, we wanted time steps that
如果我们希望之前发生的时间步
occurred earlier in time to have a much greater say.
权重更大 该怎么办
Well, then instead of maximizing this sum,
我们不再最大化这个和
the idea is that we'll maximize a different sum with rewards
而是最大化另一个不同的和
that are farther along in time are multiplied by smaller values.
时间越远的奖励将乘以更小的值
We refer to this sum as discounted return.
我们将这种和称之为折扣回报
By discounted, we mean that we'll change the goal to care more about
折扣是指我们将更改目标
immediate rewards rather than rewards that are received further in the future.
更关心近期奖励 而不是遥远未来获得的奖励
But how do we choose what values to use here?
但是如何选择这里的值呢？
Well, in practice, we'll define what's called a discount rate,
我们将定义一个折扣率
which is always denoted by the Greek letter gamma,
用希腊字母 γ 表示
and is always a number between zero and one.
它始终是 0 到 1 之间的值
Then, as for the values,
对于要乘以的值
the first term is multiplied by gamma.
第一项乘以 γ
The second term is multiplied by gamma square.
第二项乘以 γ2
Then, gamma to the third power and so on.
然后乘以 γ3 以此类推
In this way, we have a nice T.K.
这样就可以很好地表示
where rewards that occur earlier in time are always multiplied by a larger number.
更早发生的奖励始终乘以更大的数字
It's important to note that this gamma is not something that's learned by the agent.
要注意的是 该 γ 值并非由智能体学习获得
It's something that you set to refine the goal that you have for the agent.
而是由你来设置 以便优化智能体的目标
So how exactly might you set the value of gamma?
那么如何设置 γ 的值？
Let's begin by looking at what happens when we set gamma to one.
我们先看看如果将 γ 设为 1 会发生什么
So we plug in one everywhere we see gamma and we see it yields the original,
全部代入 1 结果变成了
completely un-discounted return from the previous videos.
在上个视频中提到的完全无折扣回报
And what about when gamma is set to zero?
如果将 γ 设为 0 呢？
In this case, every term in this sum
这样的话 该求和公式中的每一项都消失了
disappears with the exception of the most immediate reward.
只有最近的奖励还存在
In this way, we see that the larger you make gamma,
我们发现 γ 的值越大
the more the agent cares about the distant future.
智能体对遥远未来的关注就越高
And as gamma gets smaller and smaller,
当 γ 越来越小时
we get increasingly extreme discounting,
折扣率就越高
where in the most extreme case,
在最极端的情形下
the agent only cares about the most immediate reward.
智能体值关注最近的奖励
It's important to note that discounting is particularly relevant to continuing tasks.
值得注意的是 折扣与连续性任务的关系最大
Remember that a continuing task is one where
连续性任务是指智能体与环境的互动
the agent environment interaction goes on without end.
一直持续下去 不会结束
In this case, if the agent wants to maximize
在这种情况下 如果智能体想要最大化累积奖励
cumulative reward while it's a pretty difficult task if the feature is limitless.
但是未来是无限的 这样目标实现起来就很困难
So we use discounting to avoid having to look too far into the limitless future.
因此我们使用折扣避免无限未来的奖励产生不良的影响
But it's important to note that with or without discounting,
但是注意 无论是否有折扣
the goal is always the same.
目标始终不变
It's always to maximize cumulative reward.
一直都是最大化累积奖励
The discount rate comes in when the agent chooses actions at an arbitrary time step.
当智能体在随机时间步选择动作时 就要用到折扣
It uses the discount rate as part of its program for picking actions.
它在选择动作时 会用到折扣率
And that program is more interested in securing rewards that come sooner
程序更关注于获得更早出现的奖励
and are more likely than the rewards that come later and are less likely.
而不是稍后出现并且可能性更低的奖励
You'll learn more about how exactly the agent should select actions in the next lesson.
你将在下节课详细了解智能体应该如何选择动作
For now, we'll focus on fully specifying the reinforcement learning problem.
暂时我们将侧重于完全指定强化学习问题